

BIPIN JAGDALE

Software Test Specialist

San Diego, California, United States of America

Phone number: 3511330743(Others)

9135803679(Others)

Email: 6wiwae@gmail.com

Summary

TBD

Test Engineer

5 years of Experience in Software testing (Manual) With Android and Windows 8 platform and LTE(4G)/UMTS/CDMA/iDEN technologies.

I have been in Mobile Phone Software Testing Life Cycle, including understanding of requirements, Test Plan, Test designing, Test Case Development, Test enhancements, Verification, Test Execution and Effective reporting.

Experienced in Verizon application testing.

VolTE and VilTE testing.

Experienced in customer acceptance testing on Verizon network.

Performed BOTA/FOTA testing on LTE/UMTS/CDMA based devices.

Also experienced in Stability and Stress test activates using Automation tools.

Experience in GPS navigation testing on different platform e.g. Android, Windows.

Experienced in Qualcomm based hardware's for call processing physical layer testing.

Performed Intensive Manual Testing, and have experience in Test Management tool and Defect Management tools IBM Clear Quest and JIRA.

Proficient with testing strategies like Integration testing, Functional testing, System testing and Regression testing.

Experienced in all phases: Requirement Analysis, Unit/System Testing.

Experienced in different testing methods like - Ad-hoc Testing, Regression, Sanity,

Performance Test, Battery consumption, Inter-Operability Test and Interaction Test.

Regular coordination of Defect logging, verifying fixed Defects and Defect tracking activities.

Involved in reviews of test documents and preparation of Test Report and Bug Report. Experienced in Current drain automation testing.

Also experienced in Bluetooth automation test tool development using embedded C



language.

Also experienced in Stability test activates and battery performance tests using Automation tools.

Expertise

Quality Assurance (99%)

Skills

Sending, Architecture, Monkey, Hd, Tester, Dispatch, Strategic Planning, Test Case Execution, Test Preparation, Appium, Test Case Writing, Test Case Generation, Software Testing, Microsoft Excel, Clear Quest, Test Plan, Technology, Dms, Import, Windows Xp, Iden, Sanity Testing, Automation Testing, Perfecto, Music, Onsite, Xflash, Module, Requirements Analysis, Feature Testing, Feature, Operating Systems, Communication, Team, Android, Automation, Product, Software, Defect Logging, Opst, Analysis, Performance Testing, Stability, Volte, Windows 8, Preparation, Coordination, Alm, E-Mail, Adb, Ibm, Mobile, Catering, Multimedia, Embedded C, Test Scripts, Responsibilities, Vss, Cdma, Maintenance, Oqdm, Srlte, Stability Testing, Windows Phone, Location, Basics, Lte, Test Execution, Writing, Regression Testing, Umts, Leadership, Test Cases, Android Emulator, Oxdm, Understanding, Test Management Tool, Browser, Platform, Linux, Jira, 3g, Calling, Design, Sanity, Packet, Selenium Webdriver, Voicemail, System, System Testing, Java, Team Leadership, Deployment, Subscriptions, Test Automation Tools, Sms, Robot, Hindi, Risk Analysis, Windows 7, Rsdlite, Mms, English, Generation, Basic, Test Data, Defect Tracking, Mumbai, Test, Manual Testing, Voice, Integration Testing, Motorola, User Acceptance Testing, Microsoft Word, Video, Test Environment Setup, 4g, Microsoft Office, Citrix, Reviewer, India, Server, Radiocomm, Data, Messaging, Authentication, Customer, Python, Istqb, Bluetooth, Player, Jenkins, Tool, Software Testing Life Cycle, Defect, Verification, Battery, Coordinator, Validation, Test Suites, Rss, Cq, Cpedit, Test Scenarios, Environmental, Testing, Reporting, Functional Testing, Jobvite, Forwarding

Social Links

Linkedin https://www.linkedin.com/in/bipin-jagdale-0a1b1318



Experience

Software Test Specialist at BlackBerry

Jan 2017 - present

Senior Test Engineer at Sony Mobile Communications

Nov 2013 - present

Evaluate customer's business requirements, needs & objectives and transform same to company processes & solutions.

Analyzing Verizon requirements and developing test suits for same.

Performing Manual extensive testing on Verizon applications.

Working on Telephony test using VoLTE and ViLTE features.

SRLTE feature testing.

Executing automation test tool for stability testing and analyzing the test results.

Working on Battery performance testing.

Working on Performance testing.

Google applications testing.

Preparing Sanity test scope according to the requirement.

Daily Sanity Check.

Working on Black screen testing for stress testing on device.

Working on Monkey execution.

Defect logging and Verification.

Focus and Regression test.

Software upgrade testing(FOTA).

ROLE:

- Manual test case execution
- · Test case development
- · Automation tools maintenance.
- · Bugs tracking/reporting and Verification.
- · Executing Performance tests.
- · Reporting on daily tasks.

Evaluate customer's business requirements, needs & objectives and transform same to company processes & solutions. Analyzing Verizon requirements and developing test suits for same. Performing Manual extensive testing on Verizon applications. Working on Telephony test using VoLTE and ViLTE features. SRLTE feature testing. Executing automation test tool for stability testing and analyzing the test results. Working on Battery



performance testing. Working on Performance testing. Google applications testing. Preparing Sanity test scope according to the requirement. Daily Sanity Check. Working on Black screen testing for stress testing on device. Working on Monkey execution. Defect logging and Verification. Focus and Regression test. Software upgrade testing (FOTA). ROLE: · Manual test case execution · Test case development · Automation tools maintenance. · Bugs tracking/reporting and Verification. · Executing Performance tests. · Reporting on daily tasks.

QA Test Engineer at Motorola Solutions

Apr 2013 - Oct 2013

Worked as test engineer in test case writing and test suite preparation of Current Darin And Bluetooth test scenarios for Android phone based mobile handset with UMTS (3G) technology and local Environmental set-up.

Also involved in the development of automation test tool to test battery performance.

Tools & Technologies: DT robot (CD) tool, BT automation tool.

Roles and Responsibilities:

- · Test case development
- · Manual test case execution
- Bugs tracking/reporting
- · Involved in development of DT robot tool.
- · Module Coordinator, Defect Verifier, Defect Logger, Reviewer.

Coordinating with Client and testing team / Onsite Team for test suite preparation.

- · Test case writing.
- · Preparation of end-to-end system level test cases.
- · Communication with developers regarding analysis of the defects

And understanding of features

· Flowcharts for internal and external presentation purpose.

Worked as test engineer in test case writing and test suite preparation of Current DarinAnd Bluetooth test scenarios for Android phone based mobile handset withUMTS (3G) technology and local Environmental set-up.Also involved in the development of automation test tool to test battery performance.Tools & Technologies: DT robot (CD) tool, BT automation tool.Roles and Responsibilities: · Test case development · Manual test case execution · Bugs tracking/reporting · Involved in development of DT robot tool. · Module Coordinator, Defect Verifier, Defect Logger, Reviewer.Coordinating with Client and testing team / Onsite Team for test suite preparation. · Test case writing. · Preparation of end-to-end system level test cases. · Communication with developers regarding analysis



of the defectsAnd understanding of features · Flowcharts for internal and external presentation purpose.

Test Engineer at Motorola

Jul 2010 - Mar 2013

- -Worked as a test engineer for validating the android native applications on various Smart Phones. Also provide feature conformance testing before every product release. Remote Device Testing to facilitate network compatibility. Execute the project with core focus on Feature Testing, defect validation and Deployment.
- -Worked as an system tester in testing of Android based mobile handset with UMTS (3G) technology and local environmental set-up. The process includes Development of Manual Test Cases and Automation Test Scripts, Manual execution of Test cases, Emulation of scenarios and reporting of Defects in the product.

Tools & Technologies: xFlash, CpEdit, RSS, Test Central, Java Application Loader (JAL), Citrix Clear Quest, VSS,DDMS (Dalvik Debug Monitor Server)

Roles and Responsibilities:

- · Requirement Analysis & Design.
- · Flashing the devices with different images using xFlash.
- · Calling, Packet Data,
- · Dispatch (PTL, PTM, PTT, and PTV),
- · MotoTalk (Motorola Prop),
- · Test Environment setup.
- · Test data generation.
- · Daily Test Preparation and Execution Reports.
- · Coordinating with Client and testing team / Onsite Team.

-Worked as a test engineer for validating the android native applicationson various Smart Phones. Also provide feature conformance testing beforeevery product release. Remote Device Testing to facilitate networkcompatibility. Execute the project with core focus on Feature Testing, defectivalidation and Deployment.-Worked as an system tester in testing of Android based mobile handset with UMTS (3G)technology and local environmental setup. The process includes Development of Manual Test Cases and Automation Test Scripts, Manual execution of Test cases, Emulation of scenarios and reporting of Defects in the product. Tools & Technologies: xFlash, CpEdit, RSS, Test Central, Java Application Loader (JAL), Citrix Clear Quest, VSS, DDMS (Dalvik Debug Monitor Server) Roles and Responsibilities: Requirement Analysis & Design. Flashing the devices with different



images using xFlash. · Calling, Packet Data, · Dispatch (PTL, PTM, PTT, and PTV), · MotoTalk (Motorola Prop), · Test Environment setup. · Test data generation. · Daily Test Preparation and Execution Reports. · Coordinating with Client and testing team / Onsite Team.

Educations

■ Bachelor's degree in Electronics Engineering at Shivaji University 2005 - 2009

Certifications

- ISTQB (Basic Level) by ISTQB International Software Testing Qualifications Board April 2012
- istqb international software testing qualifications board